Wealth, Fame, Power.
Gold Roger, the King of the Pirates,
attained this and everything
else the world had to offer,
and his dying words drove
countless souls to the seas.
You want my treasure?
You can have it.
I left everything I gathered
together in one place.
Now you just have to find it.
These words lured men to
the Grand Line in pursuit
of dreams greater than
they'd ever dared to imagine.
This is the time known
as the Great Pirate Era.
Come aboard and bring along
all your hopes and dreams.
Together we will find everything
that we're looking for.
One Piece.
Compass left behind,
it'll only slow us down.
Your heart will be your guide,
raise the sails and take the helm.
That legendary place that
the end of the map reveals.
Is only legendary till
someone proves it real.
Through it all, through
all the troubled times.
Through the heartache
and through the pain.
Know that I will be there to stand by you.
Just like I know you'll stand by me.
So come aboard and bring along.
All your hopes and dreams.
Together we will find everything.
That we're looking for.
There's always room for you.
If you wanna be my friend.
We are, we are on a cruise.
We are.
Oh, my goodness.
That
crazy
rubber
guy beat Captain Kuro.
Not even the Marines
were a match for Kuro.
You're a man of a thousand plans,
and this guy still beat him!
Just...
just who are you?
I'm Monkey D. Luffy.
The only time a pirate should
abandon his name is when he dies.
I would never lose to a
coward who ditches his name,
betrays his friends, and
runs from life on the sea.
Uh, Luffy?
I never heard that name before.
You should remember my name
for the rest of your lives.
Cause one of these days, I'm
gonna be king of the pirates!
You are?
Now get out of here!
And never come back!
You did good, Luffy.
I'd expect even you to collapse
after what you just went through?
Say
Tell me, why were you so mad earlier?
Because I truly hate people like them.
They're so wrong.
That is not how friends should act.?
What are you talking about?
Of course it isn't.
Most pirates aren't the brave, honorable
people you always make them out to be!
I want some meat.
Oh, you're unbelievable!
Hey guys, think you can keep everything
that just happened here secret?
What? A secret?
Why wouldn't we want to
keep all this a secret?
Yeah, why, huh?
We put our lives on the
line to save the village!
Now everyone will change
their opinion of you,
so instead of being Usopp the
liar, you'll be Usopp the hero!
Really, Usopp?
You need to clear up
this misunderstanding.
Misunderstanding?
I was known as the Village Liar
because I lied all the time, Ms.
Kaya.
They were right not to believe me.
Besides, there's no point in scaring
people with something that's already over.
And I seriously doubt that any more pirates
like Kuro and his gang will show up.
There's no reason for pirates to attack
our out-of-the-way little village.
So listen up, pretend
this never happened, okay?
This was all just another
one of my great big lies
Now I won't force you to, but...
No, I can do it.
I'll do whatever it takes for
the good of the village, Captain!
Yeah, me too! Me too!
My lips are totally sealed, I promise!
I don't care who you allow is
Call, will you? Will you tell?
No.
Something just isn't right this morning.
Where is Usopp?
It kind of throws everything
off if he's not around.
I feel so bored.
Mama?
Is that screaming liar guy
not coming to town today?
That lying little twerp.
Where the heck is he?
You don't think I hurt his
feelings yesterday, do you?
Oh, don't worry.
He'll be up to his old tricks in no time.
I hope so.
Thanks, guys.
I wouldn't have been able to
protect the village without you.
Give credit where credit's due.
If you'd just stood by and done nothing,
I wouldn't have done anything either.
Yeah, same here.
Who cares about any of that?
I've got my hands on this sweet, sweet
treasure now, and I couldn't be happier.
Everything that happened
here today helped me.
I've just come to a
very difficult decision.
Huh?
Captain Usopp, what did you
want to talk to us about?
The three of you fought well against
those terrible black cat pirates.
As captain, I'm proud of you for
being so brave and courageous.
Thanks to you,
we overcame our biggest and most important
battle since we formed the Usopp Pirates
five years ago That was when you three
brave soldiers were only four years old,
remember?
Yeah.
Now I know this is sudden,
but I've decided that I'm going
to set out to sea by myself!
I'm finally going to leave this
place and become a real pirate.
At first I wasn't sure what I would do.
I couldn't decide if I wanted
to stay here forever or not.
But once I saw them, I knew
deep in my heart what I must do.
I feel that, as a man, I must
set out to the vast ocean.
So, I'm leaving this place behind.
I leave for one reason.
When the great pirate flag
beckons, you must heed its call!
Captain, say it isn't so?
You're lying again, right?
Isn't that a bit hasty?
There's no reason to leave.
I thought you loved this village.
And what's gonna happen to
the Usopp pirates without you?
You've been so good to me.
Guys, I plan to leave without
telling the villagers.
Give them my regards.
Captain, no, I don't want to.
Don't go, Captain!
Just stay here, please!
Usopp Pirates, do you remember this place?
This is where we first met
and formed the Usopp Pirates.
Finished!
Hey, it's that liar guy. Huh?
Who are you guys?
And why are you so buddy-buddy with me?
Well, Dai, you're famous!
Yeah, you're a really famous guy.
Right, I know.
You've come face to face with a man that
is known the world over as Captain Usopp.
Actually, everyone in the
village calls you liar, Usopp.
Okay, from this day forth, you're
officially members of the Usopp Pirates.
Come on! Man up!
A lot's happened since then, huh?
A Cerberus!
Scare it away!
A dragon!
Flower storm!
You're amazing, Captain!
But of course, I'm a
brave warrior of the sea!
Please don't talk about the old days!
I can't stand it!
Pepper's right, it's much too painful.
This kind of life isn't like you, Captain!
It's not fun!
Why would you say that
you're going to leave us?
You're not serious, are you?
You're being stupid, Captain. Stupid.
All right, men.
Tell me what all your ambitions are.
When I crawl out, my
dream is to run a pub.
My whole life I've wanted
to be a master carpenter.
My goal is to become a writer.
Then, swear to me now that each of
you will continue on your paths.
Promise me that you will never let
the fires of your ambitions die out!
As of today, our group,
the Usopp Pirates...
...are disbanded!
Now that we've eaten, we
should probably get going.
Yeah, you're right.
Here you are.
Hello there, miss.
Are you all right being out of bed?
Yes.
I think now I can truly
start recovering. You see,
my sickness this last year was caused by
the mental shock of losing both my parents.
And Usopp's friendship helped
me start getting better.
I can't stay in bed forever, you know.
I've prepared a present for
you from the bottom of my heart
to show you how grateful I am
for everything you've done here.
I'd be honored if you'd accept it.
All packed.
Guess it's farewell to this house, too.
Hey!
I can't get out!
This stupid backpack!
The real Caravelle!
Are you actually giving this to us?
As a token of my appreciation.
It's a slightly older model,
but I personally designed it
and she sails like a dream.
She has a carvel-made Caravelle with
Latine sails and a central stern rudder.
She's a fine ship and her
name is the Going Mary.
Allow me to explain the rigging.
First, about the Kruger
net yard adjustment.
It may seem a little temperamental.
Hold on, you'd be better off just
explaining the technical stuff to me.
What a cool ship.
Have you guys seen the front?
It's totally awesome.
We've loaded it with all the provisions
you might need on a long voyage.
Thanks.
It leaves nothing to be tired.
That leaves nothing to be desired, idiot.
Somebody stop this thing!
Oh, no, it's time!
Hey, what's he doing?
Looks fun.
Well, we better stop him.
That weirdo is on a collision
course with our boat.
Oh, hey, thanks, Kaya. Anytime.
You're really doing it.
You're gonna take to the ocean.
Yeah.
I've decided to get going before
I have time to change my mind.
Don't stop me.
I won't.
I know it's time for you to go.
Kaya, don't be sad about it.
Just think, the next
time I come back here,
I'll tell you about adventures that'll
sound more like lies than my old lies.
Good.
I'll look forward to it.
You guys take care!
I hope we meet again sometime!
How come?
Well, because I...
Are you antisocial or something?
I'm taking off for life on the high seas,
and I hope that we'll eventually
meet again, that's all!
What are you talking about?
Get on already. Huh?
We're friends, right? So get on.
This is it!
I'm really a pirate captain now!
Don't be stupid, Usopp!
I'm the captain!
There goes the captain.
He fell in with some pretty awesome
people, so I'm not too worried.
Yeah, he'll be safe with them.
I've never seen anybody
as strong as they are.
He's always talked
about becoming a pirate,
and now he's headed
off to live his dreams.
You know, the villagers are going to
be sad when we break the news to them.
Our captain was the only person who
could liven things up around here.
Now he's gone.
Hey, I just had a great idea!
What is it?
Mary? Yes?
Lying hurts, a lot Are you
referring to Klahadore?
No
You must be talking about Usopp?
You really wanted him to stay, didn't you?
Miss Kaya
Years ago,
one of the villagers told me a story
about your good friend Usopp's childhood.
Only a short time after his father
left the village to become a pirate,
his mother, whom he was
very close to, passed away.
Pirates!
Pirates are here!
Pirates are here, Mom!
They're here!
Hold on, Usopp.
You mustn't shout.
Calm down.
Mom, we're saved!
Dad finally came back for us!
There you go with your
wild imagination again.
You silly boy. It's true!
He always said he'd come back for us and
take us with him when you got better,
didn't he, Mom?
Usopp, my dear, your father
won't be coming back.
But I'm proud to have married such a
brave man who dared to chase his dreams.
I heard about a special medicine.
This stuff can cure any sickness!
So silly.
You dream too much.
I am a dreamer!
And I'm silly!
It's true!
I'm proud of it!
After all, I'm the son of a pirate!
Promise me one thing.
Promise me you'll grow
up to be brave like him.
PIRATES ARE COMING!
Perhaps out of loneliness,
he continued to shout it
after his mother passed away,
in the hopes that one day his father's
pirate ship would be at the shore?
ready to spirit him away to the sea and
give him a family that he never had.
The villagers say that his outlandish
lies contain his most heartfelt wish.
Pirates!
Pirates are coming!
As someone else who lost both parents,
he saw you as a kindred spirit, and he
couldn't sit by and ignore your suffering.
Now it's time for you, too,
to rise from the ashes
of tragedy and live up
to the example that Usopp
worked so hard to set.
Yes.
Cheers to a new ship
and a new Gourmet! Yeah!
They said they were fighting
to live, not to die.
Usopp's wild stories and outlandish lies
always spoke of the joy of being alive.
They helped me through my grief by
cheering me up and telling me to live.
Indeed.
Okay, we're really doing this?
You bet!
We're going to follow in our
great captain's footsteps.
We're going to dance.
Pottery!
Pottery! Pottery!
My life starts now, Mary.
I'm going to be a doctor.
That's wonderful, Miss Kaya.
Just wonderful.
Yay!
Yay, everybody!
As a kid, I never stopped.
Searching for a great treasure!
I had a map in my mind.
That I knew would lead me.
I had to find my way to that place!
Before someone could beat me.
The promised land was in my grasp.
And I wouldn't let go!
La, la, la, la.
My only dream.
La, la, la, la, la.
I won't stop chasing
it until it comes true!
But if the world ever changes,
I call out your name.
We return to the time when
everything's the same.
As long as I'm with you,
my memories don't fade.
Waiting for that one true dream?